Janmejay S Purohit

janmejayspurohit@gmail.com | +1 (929)-593-8209 | linkedin.com/in/jsp324 | janmejay.info

SUMMARY

I am currently pursuing Masters in Computer Science at Indiana University Bloomington and am actively seeking 2023-Summer internship opportunities. I have over 3 years of work experience as a full stack Javascript developer and am looking forward to pursue working in the same domain. My goal is to obtain a software developer position utilizing my strong programming skills and experience in developing, testing and implementing software solutions to improve efficiency and productivity for a company.

EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer II, Tesark Technologies Pvt. Ltd.

Sep 2019 - Jul 2022

Started my career here as Software Engineer I, and worked on multiple projects primarily as a full stack Javascript developer. My main responsibilities included working with software development and testing team members to design and develop robust solutions to meet client requirements for functionality, scalability and performance. I eventually was made responsible for researching and evaluating new technologies and software development methodologies, creating software development plans and schedules, leading software engineering teams and monitoring and optimizing software performance towards the end of my tenure.

${\bf Software\ Development\ Engineer\ Intern},\ {\bf Box} 8$

Jan 2019 - Aug 2019

Extensively worked on API integrations with Ruby on Rails as the backend. Integrated various payment gateways like Google pay, Paytm, PhonePe. Worked on various bug fixes and improvements in the in-house application as well.

Software Engineer Intern, EzPG

Jun 2018 - Dec 2018

Worked on PHP for application development, integrated features like search, sort, filter and manage hotel bookings.

EDUCATION

Master of Science, Computer Science

Aug 2022 - Present

Indiana University Bloomington

GPA: 3.9

Bachelor of Technology, Computer Science and Engineering

Aug 2015 - May 2019

Dayananda Sagar University

GPA: 9.21/10

SKILLS

Frameworks: NodeJS, ReactJS, NextJS, ExpressJS, AngularJS, Ruby on Rails, Django

Programming Languages: JavaScript, Python, Ruby, Java, C, C++

Software Packages: Jupyter Notebook, Postman, Git, Heroku, AWS - S3, EC2, RDS

Databases: PostgreSQL, MongoDB, Redis, MySQL

Projects

DSU Digital Library

Aug 2016 - Apr 2019

Contributed to front-end as well as back-end development of DSU Digital Library to host educational PDFs, Books, DVDs and linked various E-Learning resources to provide e-learning for students at the college library, developed with Python Django using Bootstrap, HTML, CSS and Postgres as the database.

Smart Fish Tracking

Sep 2017 - Mar 2018

Built a moving fish detection software on matlab that detects whether a fish is pregnant or not based on backgroud subtraction, linear regression and Kalman Filters. Based on the shape of the fish it promtps whether a fish is pregnant or not, which results in reduction of catching pregnant fishes during fishing. More details of this can be found on my portfolio.

ICICC Website Development

Dec 2018 - May 2019

Developed a website for the ICICC International Conference held at Dayananda Sagar University on 7th 8th July 2019, using Vanilla JS

Vydhya

Aug 2022 - Dec 2022

Worked on the front-end part of an engaging Patient Management System as part of my Software Engineering Course at IUB. A patient management system is a software application that helps healthcare providers store and track patient information, appointments, and medical records. As a front-end developer using React, my job was to design and develop the user interface for the system. This involved creating and implementing user-friendly layouts, forms, and visual elements, as well as ensuring that the system is responsive and easy to navigate.

Portfolio Website

May 2018

Built a portfolio to showcase my skills and abilities in web development, design, and user experience. I was responsible for designing and building the website from scratch, using technologies such as HTML, CSS, and JavaScript. I made sure to incorporate a visually appealing and user-friendly layout, and made sure the website is responsive and accessible across all devices. It also includes features such as contact form, About Me section, resumes and links to your social media profiles.